Come tears or laughs, this
is the end of it all!
Let's cap off our training
camp with a big victory, guys!
Yeah!
Okay, this is it. Let's throw
everything we have at 'em!
Huh?
You really are just a one-trick pony!
And let me tell you,
I know plenty of ways to deal with those!
Corner to corner...
They're doing an...
...overload formation!
Watch the other side! Adjust your positions!
Trying to get me with another fake?!
Defensive foul on #4! Basket
counts! One free-throw!
That's not enough... for
you to beat our team.
Dammit! Don't fuck with me!
The day that you quit playing basketball...
Do you remember what it
is you said to me, Senpai?
Huh?
Back then... you lied straight to my face...
...and I have never forgiven you for it.
Kagami ni senaka mukete ayumu
hodo ni toozakaru yume yo
Massugu kimi to mukiaitai
Dekinai jibun e to "never mind"
Ahiru no Sora
Nagare sagyou de waketeyuku yume
Muki? Fumuki? Iwaba rongai?
Koe mo naku kietetta koe
Tameiki sura denai
Hito no sei ni shitatte owarenai
Me no mae ni kiritatta ima
"Koetai" to kokoro ga sakenderu
Dekinai wake o sagasu nara daredemo dekiru sa
Agaki hashitta sono saki
mada shiranai jibun to deau
Kabe ni kizamikonda rakugaki to "never mind"
Ima asu e to hazume
Higher Than Anyone
Sweet! He made the free-throw, too!
Way to go, Konishi!
Keep it up! Keep it up!
Kuzuryu
Kitasumiyoshi
Kitasumi! Kitasumi! Kitasumi!
Wait just a damn second!
What the hell do you mean I "lied" to you?!
Cut it out, Momoharu.
We're in the middle of a game.
If they score, then we score right back!
Make sure you keep the ball moving!
Senpai...
Hey! Konishi!
What the heck was that?
You played junior basketball,
so you should know better!
Seriously, don't screw up our 2-man drills.
I'm sorry!
Whatever.
Go practice the basics
with the other newbies.
Uh, okay! Sorry again!
Momoharu! Dude! You should at least be able
to do layups by now!
You're making us look bad
in front of the new guys!
Huh? Who cares about that crap?!
There ain't nothing wrong with being sucky!
I'm still just learning the steps, you know!
I think you mean "learning the ropes," dude.
You're so stupid.
Everybody knows what I mean!
And stop snacking on shit during practice, dammit!
That guy is a riot! I've
never had a Senpai like him!
"There's nothing wrong
with being sucky," really?
He's so cool...
Thanks for the practice session!
Make sure everything gets locked up!
Freshmen, you're all on mop duty!
Oh, hey. Don't bother putting the board away.
Huh?
Because I'm gonna use it.
U-use it? But team practice
is over for today...
Shut your face, dummy.
Hurry and go home already.
Uh, okay...
Everybody makes him stay and work overtime.
That's how bad he sucks.
I practice late cuz I WANT to!
Um, then... would it be okay if I joined you?
Huh?
Sure, but only if you fetch me
a yakisoba sandwich. And pay for it.
O-okay! Right away!
Dude!
Jeez, you're outta shape.
I'm sorry...!
We run so much during team practice already...
but you still do this extra stuff every day?
Is basketball really a sport...
that requires all of this effort to play?
If you want to get good, yeah.
But it'll take even more
than this to get there.
If I put in more effort... do you think
I could become good, too?
Hell if I know, man.
Looking at you now, I'd say no.
You feelin' okay, Konitan?
Man, you look as stable on
your feet as a baby deer.
U-um... my house is over this
way, so please excuse me.
Sure. Bye-bye.
G-goodbye.
Hey!
Ah, yes?
See ya tomorrow, dude!
Okay.
When did I ever lie? I've
had enough of your bullshit!
You know that I hate lying,
and I hate being lied to even more!
He ignored my sign!
Go to the outside, Momoharu!
Momoharu?!
Nice block!
Konishi's totally got the
advantage on that guy!
Sweet! We got the ball!
We've totally stolen all the
momentum from Kuzu High!
That was a totally reckless move, Captain!
You should have jus-
Shut up!
They're gonna come at us from one side again!
Look out for any moves in low-post!
Senpai, have you really forgotten...
...what happened back then?
Kitaoka
Nakahara
Whoa, that comeback was nuts!
They actually beat Kitaoka Middle!
Dude, Hoshino was on fire out there!
Guys with talent like him
are on another level!
You can say that again! I'm totally jealous.
Hey, Momoharu! I learned how to pull off
a between-the-legs dribble!
See? Just watch this!
You dummy. Flashy moves like that
ain't gonna help you in a real game.
Uh, but, hey! The fact I did it has given me confidence
that I can improve even more.
So it makes me happy just the same!
It's been a year since I started
extra practice with you.
I'm honestly so glad that I
decided to do that, Senpai!
Where's this all coming from? I'm not gonna reward you
for sucking up to me, man.
Uh, no! That's not what I was trying to do...
Let's keep practicing more and more,
until we're some of the best players around!
Okay, well, I have to go this way.
Goodbye for today.
Konishi... listen, I...
Oh, that reminds me. Tomorrow's Monday,
which means we don't have any team practice.
But once class is over, I'll rush to get the gym keys
so we can practice alone!
Let's give it our best again tomorrow!
Sure. See ya tomorrow, dude.
Okay! I'm looking forward to it!
Thanks for all you did today!
But that was the end of it all,
because you never came back.
Even so, Momoharu, I...
...I kept going until I got good!
Rebound!
Ugh, that damn idiot!
Hell yeah! He made two in a row!
Konishi is on fire right now!
That #4 doesn't have enough
skills to stop him!
Alright! Let's keep pushing
into low-post to score!
You need to sub out, Momoharu.
If you've run out of fight,
you're only going to drag us down.
Nanao! Call a timeout!
Something weird is going on with the Captain!
Sub him out with Yashuhara for now!
Momoharu...
I get it.
Konishi never stopped... he
kept it up all by himself...
That's not enough... for
you to beat our team.
There's no way a loser like me can compete
with dedication like that...
Momoharu!
Hey, Momoharu!
Are you all right?! Do you have
a stomachache or something?
Did you eat anything weird
before the match started?!
Something is really wrong with your face!
Huh?!
Ah, no! I mean you look pale!
Oh, I know! This must be a side effect
from Madoka's cooking!
That was such a killer meal, literally!
Uh, yeah...
What the heck, Sora?!
Piss off, there's nothing wrong with me.
You heard him, Nanao! No substitution!
Dumbass! You don't call the shots around here!
If we don't do somethi-
Don't worry!
I know Momoharu won't lose
to anybody out on the court!
Are you nuts?! That's not the problem
we're talking about here!
Okay, Chiaki! Let's hurry
and pass the ball in!
Listen here!
Defense! Defense! Defense!
Nice move, Katori!
Offense! Offense! Offense!
Stupid shorty! This exactly why I said
we should sub him out!
Defensive foul, #11!
Awesome! Free-throws for us!
I was expecting him to dodge me.
Never thought he'd shoot it straight.
I guess he just totally outwitted me.
Oh, please, that was on purpose.
This jerk!
Is holding the team back all I know
how to do? Seriously?
Momoharu!
They've got two free-throws.
We're counting on you for any rebounds!
Show me one more time,
what it looks like to fly!
Okay, Momoharu!
Let's hurry over to the gym.
I want to see that move of yours one more time!
Because that kid...
...lacks the greatest asset that anybody
can possibly have in basketball: height.
Sweet! Another basket!
Don't miss the second shot, Katori!
I'm really sorry, Konishi.
I did you wrong.
I might not be able to compete
with your level of skill now, but...
...I still want to get serious
about basketball again!
This kid taught me a real lesson.
That no matter what happens,
you should NEVER give up!
The shot missed!
Rebound!
Yeah! He got it!
Nice rebound!
Quit screwing up, dammit!
Oh crap!
I've been waiting for this moment!
Awesome! He got open!
Hell yeah! A three!
Kuzuryu
Kitasumiyoshi
Now we have a 9-point lead!
Keep it up, Konishi!
I love you, Nao!
Dammit.
Quit staring at the ground.
Let's go.
Right!
But actually, you were staring
at the ground earlier yourself!
Shut it.
Having a 9-point lead is total chump change!
We're gonna tie it right back up!
"I shouldn't have quit playing back then."
"I should have started
playing basketball earlier."
Drowning myself in thoughts like those
is just a waste of time.
Konishi... I am...
...going to improve alongside my teammates!
Huh?! A double screen?!
You brat!
I'm not letting you sink
another one of those!
It bounced off his hand!
Whoa!
What a jump!
Senpai...!
Jumping is the one thing that I'm better at
than everybody else.
Hell, even Jordan's got nothing on me.
O-oh really?
He never let anything hold him back.
Despite his shortcomings,
he was always full of confidence.
Momoharu... I...
...I wanted to become just like you!
HELL YEAH!
Whoa!
Momoharu found his groove!
Hmph. That numbskull.
All right! Time to get back in the game!
Let Momoharu handle all of the rebounds!
Kanagawa School of Medical Science
Secondary Hospital
Are we clear? Only 10 minutes, okay?
I'm sorry to impose.
Honestly... if any word of
this got to my boss, then...
It sure can be scary to
deal with people like him!
Don't make it sound like you're off the hook!
Good grief.
It's surprising. I had no idea this area
was so rich with beautiful foliage.
Why does that come as a surprise?
Well, I didn't expect to find
much in the city like this.
This hospital is quite far
from downtown, though.
This area is filled with nature
spots like Ryokuchi Park.
Oh?
This feels great!
She looks so lively today.
Maybe bringing her out here
was a good idea after all.
Say, Ms. Yabuuchi?
Yes?
Do you mind... if we took a little trip
further outside the hospital?
Huh?!
#11 has it! Don't let him cut in!
He stopped trying to cut
in towards the basket!
Rebound!
Natsume...
Konishi! Nice rebound!
Yasuhara, it's time! You're up!
Huh? Wait, you know that I have 4 fouls
and just one more gets me ejected...
3 minutes! No, even just 2 minutes is fine!
Out of bounds! Throw-in with
Kuzu High in possession!
Player substitution for Kuzuryu High!
Be careful not to foul.
Right!
You can't go hitting or
running into anybody, okay?
Natsume?!
Y-yo, Kite! Are you okay?!
Don't freak out. I just tripped
and had a little fall.
This sucks!
My leg is all cramped up.
A'ight! Just you wait, Kite!
I swear I'm gonna turn
this game around for us!
Hmm, seems like #11 and #15
have finally hit their limit.
I doubt they have even the
tiniest shred of stamina left.
It's a shame since they had built good momentum,
but now their 2 strongest are all tapped out.
Not having a solid bench to rely on
is an unfortunate burden, indeed...
At this point, they no longer
have any hope of winning.
Well, I must say they still
did an incredible job.
Going against man-to-man this
late in the game is rough.
Hey Chiaki!
Offensive foul! Charging!
He anticipated the shorty's move
and was waiting to block him!
Taro is such an amazing player!
Nice, Taro.
Thanks.
Rack up another win for me.
It's time for you to pack it
up and go home, little boy.
All right, boys! Let's score another one!
Not yet!
We're capable of doing so much more!
Kurumatani...
Kuzuryu
Kitasumiyoshi
He took it right down the middle!
Nice drive, Tachibana!
Kitasumi! Kitasumi! Kitasumi!
I really want them to win this...
Um, Madoka?
Your phone's been going
off for a while now...
Sorry, I got open but I couldn't sink it...
Shake it off! Time for defense!
Let's shut them down!
This is the time when I should be scoring
some damn baskets... shit!
I wanna win this!
Oh jeez! I wouldn't have answered if I knew she was
gonna make me come out here,
I'm supposed to be ref!
Madoka!
Heya!
Don't give me that! Aren't you
supposed to be at work right now?
I'm here as part of my job!
Apparently Kuzu High is in the middle
of a basketball game,
so I figured you might be
able to help us take a peek.
"Take a peek"? Why would
you want to watch it, sis?
I'm the one who wanted to come.
Ms. Yuka Kurumatani...?!
We scored again!
They can't beat us now!
Dammit! They're ahead of
us now by double digits!
They're just getting further and further ahead!
Score some damn points, you guys!
Hey, Nao. Don't you have a
plan or something to help?
That last pass you made was pretty solid.
Huh?
Tell me, do you have any experience
being a point guard?
Well, to be honest, that
was the only position
I was allowed to play when I
was younger due to my height.
I see. That makes sense.
I have a proposition.
Do you think you can commit to being
our point guard for a bit?
Huh?
I'm going... to score us some points.
Huh? Wait...
You can actually shoot the ball, Chiaki?!
Dude, how rude can you get?!
Brace yourself for a Rock Chop later.
Wha-?! But I've never seen you
even try to shoot a basket!
I thought that you must be just
as bad at shooting as Momoharu,
since you're twins and all...
We're twins, not clones!
Um, so, the reason you've
never actually tried to score
is because you weren't playing seriously?
Don't be stupid. I always play seriously
whenever I'm on the court.
It's just... I can't multitask
and manage two things at once.
I'm a pretty clumsy guy at heart, you know.
Are you up for it?
I'll do whatever it takes.
No matter what... I'm not
letting us lose this game!
Hitori ja umaku ikanaku temo
Kikkake nante tanjun sa
Mienai deguchi ni hikaru ga sashite
Asu wa soko ni arunda
Hitori nanka ja nakatta
Kono me ni utsuru keshiki no naka ni
Kimi ga ireba doko made datte ikeru sa
Kitto genkai nante nainda
Kimi to ireba tsuyoku narunda
Nando demo tachiagatte susunde ikou
Oh oh oh, oh oh oh, oh oh oh,
Saigo no ichibyou made
Akiramenaide busukatte
Kono michi no saki wa
kanarazu kagayaiteru kara
Ahiru no Sora
Next Time: Last Play
Next episode: "Last Play."